Register of the Joseph Freeman papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS (PROSE), 1912-1965
  - Letter to the editor, New Republic, Printed copy, 1941 September 1. (Folder 11)
  - Review of Jerome Mellquist, The Emergence of an American Art, Typescript, circa 1942. (Folder 12)
  - Review of Constance Rourke, The Roots of American Culture, Typescript, circa 1942. (Folder 13)
  - "How to Save Your Money," War bond promotional. Typescript and letters, 1942, 1942 June 5. (Folder 14)
  - "Stabilization of Russian Revolution," Report prepared for Fortune magazine. Letters, manuscript corrections, and mimeograph copy, 1942 October 19 (Folder 15)
  - Review of Arthur Koestler, Arrival and Departure, Typescript, circa 1943. (Folder 16)
  - Review of Anna Louise Strong, Wild River, Typescript, circa 1943. (Folder 17)
  - Never Call Retreat, 1943
    - Correspondence
      Includes letters by Floyd Dell, King Gordon, Piet Mondrian, Scott Nearing, Upton Sinclair, Agnes Smedley, Norman Thomas, Freda Utley, Ella Winter and others
      - 1941 - 1943 April (Folder 18)
      - 1943 May - 1963 (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - Drafts (Folder 2-14)
    - Drafts (Box 113, Folder 1-6)
    - Drafts (Box 114, Folder 1-4)
    - Notes and miscellany (Folder 5)
    - Notes and miscellany (Box 115, Folder 1-17)
    - Reviews and promotional material (Folder 18)
  - Memorandum on Russia, Typescript, 1943 February 23. (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - Interview, "Books are Bullets" (radio program), May. Broadcast transcript and correspondence with Bennett Cerf and another, 1943, circa 1943 (Folder 2)
  - "The Great Adventure," Typescript screenplay, 1943 June (Folder 3)
  - "The Search for Ancestors," PM, Printed copy, 1943 June 7 (Folder 4)
  - "Messiah and Hero in History," Review of Wilson D. Wallis, Messiahs, and Sidney Hook, The Hero in History. Typescript, printed copy, and letter, 1943 June 27 (Folder 5)
  - "Melodrama and Metaphysics," New Republic, Review of Hermann Borchardt, The Conspiracy of Carpenters: Historical Accounting of a Ruling Class. Typescript, letter, and printed copy, 1943 August 9 (Folder 6)
  - "The Strange Death of Dr. Plantagenet," Clipping, letters, and typescripts, 1943, 1943 September (Folder 7)
  - Review of Paul Hughes, Retreat from Rostov, Tomorrow, Typescript and printed copy, 1943 November (Folder 8)
  - Review of Martin Flavin, Journey in the Dark, Tomorrow, Notes, typescript, and printed copy, 1943 December (Folder 9)
  - "Information, Please," Contribution to a weekly radio program. Correspondence, proposed questions, guest biographies, material relating to a projected almanac, memoranda, printed matter, and miscellany, 1943 December - 1945 June. (Folder 10-14)
    Includes material relating to Freeman's U.S.O. trip to Europe in 1945
  - "Information, Please" (Box 117, Folder 1-2)
  - Review of Frank Bailey, It Can't Happen Here Again, 1944? Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence with Bailey, 1944-1945 (Folder 3)
  - "The Great Promise," Tomorrow, Typescript and printed copy, 1944 January (Folder 4)
  - Review of Joshua Trachtenberg, The Devil and the Jews, Tomorrow, Typescript and printed copy, 1944 April (Folder 5)
  - Review of Walter Duranty, U.S.S.R.: The Story of Soviet Russia, Letter and typescript, 1944, 1944 April 16. (Folder 6)
  - Review of Wanda Wasilewska, The Rainbow, Tomorrow, Typescript and printed copy, 1944 June. (Folder 7)
  - "Summer Afternoon," Tomorrow, Typescript and printed copy, 1944 August (Folder 8)
  - Review of Harold Laski, Faith, Reason and Civilization, Tomorrow, Typescript and printed copy, 1944 September (Folder 9)
  - Review of Will Durant, Caesar and Christ: A History of Roman Civilization and of Christianity from Their Beginnings to A.D. 325. Typescript and letter, 1944 October 15 (Folder 10)
  - Review of Theodor Reik, A Psychologist Looks at Love, Tomorrow, Typescript and printed copy, 1944 November (Folder 11)
  - Review of Claude Bowers, The Young Jefferson, Typescript, printed copy, and letter, 1945, circa 1945 (Folder 12)
  - Review of Ernst Cassirer, An Essay on Man, Tomorrow, Typescript and printed copy, 1945 February (Folder 13)
  - Review of Mary Column, From These Roots, Tomorrow, Typescript and printed copy, 1945 March (Folder 14)
  - Review of Harry Slochower, No Voice is Wholly Lost, Typescript and letter to Norman Cousins, 1945, 1945 April 20. (Folder 15)
  - Review of Louis Kronenberger, Reader's Companion, Typescript and correspondence, 1945, 1945 May (Folder 16)
  - "Russia and the U.S.," Life, Notes, letters, typescript, proofs, miscellany, correspondence, and printed copy, 1945, 1945 Summer (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - "U.S.S.R.--The Early Days," Nation, Review of Simon Liberman, Building Lenin's Russia. Typescript and printed copy, 1945 September 29. (Folder 2)
  - "You Wouldn't Think There's a War Going On," Short story. Typescript, 1945 Fall. (Folder 3)
  - "America's Homesick Army," Nation, (two parts). Typescripts, printed copies, and letters, 1945-1946, 1945 October 27 - November 3 (Folder 4)
  - "An Hour with Richard Strauss," Typescripts, 1946 January (Folder 5)
  - Review of Bertrand Russell, A History of Western Philosophy, Tomorrow, Typescript, letter, and printed copy, 1945-1946, 1946 February (Folder 6)
  - "So This is Love," Autobiographical writing in response to publication of Ione Robinson's memoir, A Wall to Paint On. Typescript and reviews of Robinson's book, 1946 February 17 (Folder 7-8)
  - Review of Lewis Mumford, Essays, Addresses, and Letters on Politics and Education, Typescript, 1946 March 24. (Folder 9)
  - The Long Pursuit, 1947
    - Correspondence, 1947-1949 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Drafts and fragments (Folder 2-7)
    - Drafts (Box 120, Folder 1-5)
    - Galley proofs (Folder 6)
    - Galley proofs (Box 121, Folder 1-2)
    - Notes and background material. Notebooks and a journal relating to Freeman's trip to Europe with the U.S.O. in, 1945 (Folder 3-6)
    - Promotional material and reviews (Folder 7)
  - Review of Dorothy Speare, Spring on Fifty-Second Street, 1947. Typescript and correspondence with Speare and another, 1947-1948 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - "The Triumph of Life," (co-authored with Herbert Kline). Proposed screenplay. Typescripts, outline, letters, and notes, 1947 (Folder 2)
  - "Spring Came on Forever [1947]," Outline for a novel. Typescripts, 1947 June. (Folder 3)
  - Comment on James Farrell, Literature and Morality, Typescript notes, 1947 August 20. (Folder 4)
  - "Background of American Liberalism and Socialism," Typescript fragments, 1947 November 21. (Folder 5)
  - "The Jaguar," Notes for a short story. Typescripts, 1948. (Folder 6)
  - "Born Again," (co-authored with Herbert Kline). Screenplay. Typescripts, poem, and letters, 1947, 1948 April (Folder 7)
  - "The Riddle of History," Typescript outlines and notes, 1948 May 28. (Folder 8)
  - "Variations in a Theme," Short story. Typescripts, 1949 January 24. (Box 123, Folder 1)
  - "The Snakepit," Typescript, 1949 January 31. (Folder 2)
  - "The Silver Coin," Proposed television show. Typescript and letter, 1949, 1949 September (Folder 3)
  - "The Man Who Found a Million Dollars," Short story. Typescripts and letters, 1949-1950 (Folder 4)
  - "Fable," Short story. Typescript (incomplete) and letter, 1950, 1950 April 16. (Folder 5)
  - Review of Andre Malraux, The Psychology of Art, Typescripts and letter, 1950, 1950 October 30. (Folder 6)
  - "Notes on the Psychology of Revolution," Typescript, 1950 December 26. (Folder 7-8)
  - "The Super-Enchanted," Review of Budd Schulberg, The Disenchanted. Typescripts and letter, 1951 February 1951 (Folder 9)
  - Review of Gerald Sykes, The Nice American, Typescript and letter, 1951, 1951 March 6. (Folder 10)
  - Comments on Martin Heidegger, Existence and Being, Typescript, 1951 March 14. (Folder 11)
  - "Mexico Revisited," Typescript, circa 1952. (Folder 12)
  - Outline for a projected book on U.S.-Mexican relations, Typescript, 1952 (Folder 13)
  - "The Newberry Library Conference on American Studies," Nov. Meeting report. Typescript and letter, 1952 (Folder 14)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Post, (date written). Typescript, 1953 June 25 (Folder 15)
  - Statement to the U.S. Senate (McCarthy Subcommittee), Subpoena, letter, clipping, notes, and typescript (draft?), 1953, 1953 June 30. (Folder 16)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Post, (date written). Typescript, 1954 August 25 (Folder 17)
  - "Reflections on Project X," Comments on preliminary manuscript of Ted Draper, Roots of American Communism. Typescript, 1954 December 6. (Folder 18)
  - "Two Poems for Irwin Edman: 1896-1954," American Scholar, Printed copy, biographical sketch, and letters, 1954-1955, 1955 Summer. (Folder 19)
  - "Adventures of 'The Dogface Soldier,'" Typescripts, printed material, typescript by Bert Gold, promotional material related to the movie, To Hell and Back, sheet music of the song, "The Dogface Soldier," miscellany and correspondence with Gold, Ken Hart, and another, 1955 June, 1950-1957 (Folder 20)
  - Letter to the editor, Life, (date written). Relates to the song, "The Dogface Soldier." Typescript and letter, 1955, 1955 July 7 (Folder 21)
  - Memorandum on Maksim Litvinov, Notes for a Journal, Typescript and letter to Bertram Wolfe, 1955, 1955 August (Folder 22)
  - "A Note on Ruthenberg," Typescript, 1956 March 14. (Folder 23)
  - "Reflections on the Great Change," Typescript, 1956 May 14. (Folder 24)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Herald-Tribune, Typescript, 1956 July 13. (Folder 25)
  - "First Prelude," Typescript, 1956 August 28. (Folder 26)
  - "The Tree of Knowledge," Lecture, Smith College, Northampton, Mass. Holographs and typescripts, 1957 January 15. (Folder 27)
  - "Assignment," Typescripts, 1957 June 26. (Folder 28)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Typescript, 1956 September 17 (Folder 29)
  - "No More Death," Typescript (incomplete), 1957 December 2. (Folder 30)
  - "A Heroine of Our Time: The Death of Hedda," Series of letters (to Jo Herbst?). Typescripts, 1958 October 26-28. (Box 124, Folder 1)
  - "Uncle Dennis," Typescripts, 1958 March. (Folder 2)
  - "The Vision of the Thirties," Grecourt Review, Speech, Smith College, Northampton, Massachusetts, 1958 May 7. Typescripts, printed copy, and letters, 1958, 1958 Spring. (Folder 3)
  - "The Poet Pure and Undefiled," Epistolary memoir. Typescript, 1958 June-August (Folder 4-6)
  - "The Poet Pure and Undefiled", undated (Box 125, Folder 1-2)
  - "Existentialism: What Is It All About?" Review of William Barrett, Irrational Man: A Study in Existential Philosophy. Typescripts, letters, and printed copy, 1958 October 19 (Folder 3)
  - "Hurrah for Everything! A Corrido by Miguel de Molinos," 1958-1963. Short version published in the Socialist Call, Although this is essentially a poetical work, it is included in this series because of its relation (as precursor?) to "Paradise Forever," "The Princess and the Frog," and "The Joyous Lake", 1958 June.
    Includes a preliminary version (?) entitled "The Titans"
    - General. Correspondence and miscellany, 1960-1961 (Folder 4)
    - Drafts. (Folder 5-7)
      Includes notes, fragments, and miscellaneous typescripts
    - Drafts (Box 126, Folder 1-6)
    - Drafts (Box 127, Folder 1-6)
    - Drafts (Box 128, Folder 1-5)
    - Drafts (Box 129, Folder 1)
    - Final drafts? (Folder 2-3)
  - "Hurrah for Everything! A Corrido by Miguel de Molinos"
    - Printed copy (Folder 4)
  - "Paradise Forever" Allegorical novel related to "Hurrah for Everything," "The Princess and the Frog," and "The Joyous Lake", 1958-1963.
    - General. Correspondence, introductions, and outlines, 1961-1964 (Folder 5-6)
    - Drafts
      - General (Box 130, Folder 1-7)
      - General (Box 131, Folder 1-5)
      - General (Box 132, Folder 1-6)
      - General (Box 133, Folder 1-5)
      - General (Box 134, Folder 1-6)
      - General (Box 135, Folder 1-5)
      - Final (Folder 6-7)
      - Final (Box 136, Folder 1-2)
    - Notes and fragments (Folder 3-10)
    - Notes and fragments (Box 137, Folder 1-9)
    - Notes and fragments (Box 138, Folder 1-8)
    - Notes and fragments (Box 139, Folder 1-4)
  - "The Princess and the Frog,", 1958-1962.
    NOTE: This manuscript is very similar to "Paradise Forever," but seems to have been developed concurrently with that work; also related to "Hurrah for Everything!" and "The Joyous Lake"
    - General. Outlines (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - Drafts (Folder 2-21)
    - Drafts (Box 141, Folder 1-9)
    - Fragments and notes (Folder 10-11)
  - "The Wheel," Typescript, 1959 January 9. (Box 142, Folder 1)
  - "Pasternak and Mayakovsky," Typescript (incomplete), 1959 April 7. (Folder 2)
  - "The Wild Geese," Contribution to a panel discussion. Clipping, notes, and typescripts, 1959, 1959 April 15. (Folder 3)
  - "The Best of All Possible Worlds," Contribution to a symposium at the Newberry Library, Chicago, Illinois. Typescripts, 1959 April 18. (Folder 4)
  - "A Quiet Weekend," Autobiographical fiction, 1959 August
    - General. Notes, fragments, and miscellaneous typescripts (Folder 5-9)
    - Drafts (Folder 143)
      - General (Folder 1-5)
      - Final (Box 144, Folder 1-2)
  - "Joyous Lake," Allegorical novel related to "Paradise Forever," "The Princess and the Frog," and "Hurrah for Everything!", 1959-1964.
    - General. Notes, fragements, and miscellaneous typescripts (Folder 3-5)
    - Drafts and fragments (Box 145, Folder 1-5)
    - Drafts and fragments (Box 146, Folder 1-5)
    - Drafts and fragments (Box 147, Folder 1-4)
    - Drafts and fragments (Box 148, Folder 1)
    - Final draft (Folder 2-5)
    - "The Elusive Horizon," Typescripts and holographs, 1960. (Box 149, Folder 1)
  - Notes on Donald Drew Egbert, Communism, Radicalism, and the Arts, Typescripts, 1960 January 3. (Folder 2)
  - "The Artist and the Twentieth Century Revolution," Notes on Sibyl Moholy-Nagy, Moholy-Nagy: Experiment in Totality. Typescripts, 1960 January 9. (Folder 3)
  - "Love is Always the Beginning," Typescripts, 1960 March 10. (Folder 4)
  - "The Smith Girls, the Beatniks, and the Soviet Union," Typescript (incomplete), 1960 April 5. (Folder 5)
  - "Spanish Letters," (date compiled). Collection of letters from Milton Felsen, Jack Friedman and other American volunteers during the Spanish Civil War. Typescript, 1960 April 8 (Folder 6)
  - "Exile," Autobiographical writing. Typescript, 1960 April 12. (Folder 7)
  - "The State of Dissent in America," Television symposium with Daniel Aaron, Eric F. Goldman and James Wechsler. Mimeograph transcript, 1960 April 24. (Folder 8)
  - "Memo for a Literary Project," Background memorandum explaining the development of the "Joyous Lake," "Paradise Forever," "The Princess and the Frog," and "Hurrah for Everything!" Typescripts, 1960 April-May. (Folder 9)
  - "Spotlight on the Moral Slump," Review of Frank Gibney, The Operators. Typescripts and correspondence, 1960 August 1960 (Folder 10)
  - Comment on Edvard Kardelj, Socialism and War, Typescript, 1960 November 7. (Folder 11)
  - "Love vs. Hate," Comments on the upcoming trial of Adolf Eichmann. Typescript, 1960 November 28. (Folder 12)
  - "The Absurd Adventure of an Absurd Man," Autobiographical allegory. Typescript, 1960 December 9. (Folder 13)
  - "The Red Lion," Essay collection? Notes, fragments, and typescripts, 1960-1961. (Folder 14-15)
  - "The Red Lion" (Box 150, Folder 1-3)
  - "Variations on a Theme," Typescript, circa 1961 (Folder 4)
  - "Eisenhower, Kennedy and Yugoslavia," Typescript and notes, 1961 June 20. (Folder 5)
  - "Death in the Morning," Reflections on Ernest Hemingway. Typescripts, 1961 July. (Folder 6)
  - "Montage of Presuppositions," Notes and typescripts, 1961 November (Box 151, Folder 1)
  - Letter to the editor, ARTS Magazine, (date written). Relates to the painter John Graham. Typescript, poem, and letters to Jacques Mayer, 1961, 1961 December 19 (Folder 2)
  - "The Wit and Wisdom of Francis Bacon,", 1961-1963
    - General. Correspondence, printed material, notes, and fragments, 1955-1961 (Folder 3-8)
    - Draft (Folder 9)
  - "Awakening of Spring," 1962 Jan. Review of Jonak Mekas, Guns of the Trees (film). Typescripts, film script, promotional material, clippings, correspondence with Mekas and others, 1961-1962 (Box 152, Folder 1-3)
  - "The Revival of Ernst Toller," Typescript, 1962 January 12. (Folder 4)
  - "Thoughts Out of Season," Written for Max Hayward and Pat Blake. Typescripts, 1962 January 16. (Folder 5)
  - "Tyranny," Written for the Dissenters (discussion group). Typescripts, notes, and letters to Daniel Aaron, 1962, 1962 January 31. (Folder 6)
  - "Marx and Engels on sex, love and marriage," Typescript, 1962 February 17. (Folder 7)
  - "In Memoriam: Albert Rhys Williams," Typescript and clipping (obituary by Joshua Kunitz), 1962, 1962 March 15. (Folder 8)
  - Speech, Speech prepared for Dissenters thirtieth anniversary dinner honoring Roger Baldwin. Typescripts, notes, and letters to Robert Bendiner and another, 1962, 1962 May 23. (Folder 9)
  - "Ilya Ehrenburg's Defense of Poetry," Typescripts (fragmentary) and notes, 1962 November - December (Folder 10)
  - "Ilya Ehrenburg's Defense of Poetry" (Box 153, Folder 1)
  - "The Negro in Voznosensky," Typescript (incomplete), 1963. (Folder 2)
  - "The War Between Diego Rivera and David Alfaro Siquieros--and Their Reconciliation," Typescript (incomplete), 1963 February 3 (Folder 3)
  - "1913," Relates to modern art. Typescript (incomplete), 1963 February 15. (Folder 4)
  - "McCarthy Crusade," Typescript, 1963 February 17. (Folder 5)
  - "1922-1923," Relates to the Liberator. Typescript, 1963 February 17. (Folder 6)
  - "The Horizontal, the Vertical and the Diagonal as Symbols of Man's Fate," Relates to modern art. Typescript (fragmentary) and notes, 1963 March 1. (Folder 7)
  - "The Press," Remarks to a conference of high school editors. Typescript, 1963 March 10. (Folder 8)
  - Remarks at a poety reading, Typescripts, 1963 March 12. (Folder 9)
  - "Persecution and Free Thought," Typescript (fragmentary), 1963 April 17. (Folder 10)
  - "Entuchenko," Typescript (fragmentary), 1963 April 19. (Folder 11)
  - "Notes on Poetry," Typescript (fragmentary), 1963 April 20. (Folder 12)
  - "The Alienation of Man," Typescript, 1963 April 21. (Folder 13)
  - "The Prelude," Speech relating to poetry. Typescripts, fragments, and letters, 1963, 1963 April 22. (Folder 14)
  - "Autumn 1940," Autobiographical fiction. Typescript (incomplete), 1963 May 29. (Folder 15)
  - "Abstract Art and the Revolution of Our Time," Typescript (incomplete), 1963 June 7. (Folder 16)
  - "The Rainbow," New Politics, Excerpt from "Paradise Forever"? Typescripts, printed copy, miscellany, radio broadcast script, and letters, 1963, 1963 Summer. (Folder 17)
  - Speech, Typescripts, notes, and fragments, 1963 November 6. (Box 154, Folder 1-2)
  - "Presuppositions," Typescripts, notes, and fragments, 1963 November 22. (Folder 3)
  - Comments on the assassination of John Kennedy, Typescripts and clipping, 1963, 1963 November 23. (Folder 4)
  - "Death of the President," Typescripts, 1963 December 7. (Folder 5)
  - "Voyage to the Twenties," Typescripts, 1963-1964. (Folder 6)
  - "The Ghost of Mayakovsky," Typescript, 1964 February 23. (Folder 7)
  - "First Meeting with Pilnyak," Typescript fragment, 1964 March 6. (Folder 8)
  - "The End of Guido Fabroni," Short story. Typescript, 1964 March 25. (Folder 9)
  - "The Wisdom Behind Symbolic Greek Shield of Athena Is Applied to Current Problems," News (Mexico City), Typescript, fragment, and printed copy, 1964 April 5. (Folder 10)
  - Speech, Prepared for presentation at Smith College. Typescript, 1964 April 24. (Folder 11)
  - "The Triumph of Time," Autobiographical writing. Typescript, 1964 June 3. (Folder 12)
  - Articles on Mexico, News (Mexico City), Oct. 10. Printed copies, notes, and correspondence with Alma Reed, 1964-1965, 1964 November 1 - 1965 (Folder 13)
  - "The Outlaw," Typescripts and fragments, 1964 December (Box 155, Folder 1-2)
  - "A Throw of the Dice," Autobiographical writing relating to Freeman's experiences in Russia and Europe in the late 1920s. Early version of "The Year of Grace"? Typescripts, 1965. (Folder 3)
  - "The Year of Grace," New Politics, Notes, typescripts, letters, and printed copy, 1963-1965, 1965 Winter. (Folder 4)
  - "Letters from Sergei Dinamov," Survey, Typescripts (fragmentary), printed copy, and correspondence with Walter Laqueur and another, 1963?-1965, 1965 April. (Folder 5)
- PUBLIC RELATIONS FILE, 1948-1965
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, press releases, printed matter, notes, biographical sketches, speeches and writings by others (sometimes drafted by Freeman), and miscellany. Arranged alphabetically by name of client organization.
  - General
    - General. Memoranda, letters, notes, printed matter, and miscellany, 1949-1956 (Box 156, Folder 1)
    - Edward L. Bernays
      - General. Notes, resumes, printed matter, schedules, fragments of writings by Freeman, and miscellany, 1948-1952 (Folder 2-4)
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1948-1952 (Folder 5)
        - Bernays, Edward L. and Doris Fleishman
          - 1941-1949 July (Folder 6-7)
          - 1949 August - 1955 (Box 157, Folder 1-5)
      - Press releases, Written by Freeman and others, 1948-1951 (Folder 6)
      - Speeches and writings.
        Includes material drafted or written by Freeman
        - Bernays, Edward L.
          - General, 1943-1952 (Box 158, Folder 1-2)
          - Public Relations (book), 1950-1952 (Folder 3-5)
        - Fleishman, Doris, 1951 (Folder 6)
    - Edward L. Greenfield and Company. Correspondence and proposals, 1954 (Box 159, Folder 1)
    - Executive Research (Dale Armstrong and Dave Snyder), 1950-1965 (Folder 2-3)
  - American Nurses Association. Report, letters, biographical sketch, printed matter, miscellany, and writings by Freeman, 1948-1964 (Folder 4-6)
  - American Paper and Pulp Association. Memoranda, correspondence, notes, press releases, notes, conventional material, and writings by Freeman, 1954-1961 (Box 160, Folder 1-5)
  - Hotel accounts. Notes, letters, proposals, clipping, and writings by Freeman, 1953-1958 (Box 161, Folder 1-2)
  - International Paper Company. Report, letters, speech, proposal, notes, printed matter, and writing by Freeman, 1952-1954 (Folder 3-4)
  - Lucy Stone League. Notes, pamphlet, speech, memoranda, and press releases, 1950-1951 (Folder 5)
  - Mack Trucks, Inc. Speeches, reports, press releases, memoranda, printed matter, and miscellany, 1950-1952 (Folder 6-7)
  - Mack Trucks, Inc. (Box 162, Folder 1)
  - Moles (organization of construction engineers). Letters, printed matter, speeches and writings by Freeman and others, 1949 (Folder 2-3)
  - National Association of Educational Broadcasters. Printed matter, newslettesr, speeches, and letters, 1950-1952 (Folder 4)
  - National Consumer Finance Association. Questionnaire, report, printed matter, and miscellany, 1952-1956 (Folder 5)
  - Otarion, Inc. Correspondence, 1954 (Folder 6)
  - Play of the Month Guild. Printed matter, reports, notes, draft letters, 1950-1951 (Folder 7)
  - Proctor and Gamble. Press releases, printed matter, and proposals, 1950-1951 (Folder 8)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor (memoirs). Galley proofs, press releases, report, and miscellany, 1949 (Folder 9)
  - Television Authority. Report, printed matter, press releases, and writings by Freeman, 1949-1950 (Box 163, Folder 1)
  - Yardville, U.S.A. Press releases, memoranda, reports, printed matter, letters, and writings drafted by Freeman, 1948-1949 (Folder 2-4)
  - Yugoslavia. Proposal and newsletters, 1949 (Folder 5)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1915-1964